All I can do is be me, whoever that is.
I'm Not There is a drama, music film directed by Todd Haynes.
Six actors portray six personas of music legend Bob Dylan in scenes depicting various stages of his life, chronicling his
rise from unknown folksinger to international icon and revealing how Dylan constantly reinvented himself.
Jack / Pastor John, played by Christian Bale.
Jude, played by Cate Blanchett.
Woody / Chaplin Boy, played by Marcus Carl Franklin.
Billy, played by Richard Gere.
Robbie, played by Heath Ledger.
Arthur, played by Ben Whishaw.
I'm Not There is a 2007 musical drama film directed by Todd Haynes, who co-wrote
the screenplay with Oren Moverman, based on a story by Haynes.
An experimental biographical film, it is inspired by the life and music of American singer-songwriter Bob Dylan, with six actors depicting different facets of Dylan's public
personas: Christian Bale, Cate Blanchett, Marcus Carl Franklin, Richard Gere, Heath Ledger (his final film to be released during his lifetime), and Ben Whishaw.
A caption at the start of the film declares it to be "inspired by the music and the many lives of Bob Dylan"; this is the only
mention of Dylan in the film apart from song credits, and his only appearance in it is concert footage from 1966.
The film's title is taken from the 1967 Dylan Basement Tape recording of "I'm Not There", a song that
had not been officially released until it appeared on the film's soundtrack album.
I'm Not There premiered at the 64th Venice International Film Festival on September 3, 2007, and was
released in the United States on November 21 and in Germany on February 28, 2008.
It received generally positive reviews from critics, with praise for its
acting (particularly Blanchett's), directing, and musical score.
It underperformed at the box office, grossing $11 million
worldwide on the budget of $20 million.
I'm Not There appeared on multiple publications' top ten films lists for 2007.
Blanchett won the Volpi Cup for Best Actress and the Golden Globe Award for Best Supporting
Actress, and received a nomination for the Academy Award for Best Supporting Actress.
The film explores themes of rock 'n' roll,
advancement, john f. kennedy, success, beatnik.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking.